George Fernandez

Burbank, California, United States



jdecorum@gmail.com



(818)970-2371



linkedin.com/in/george-fernandez-7b773b19

Summary

A production professional with over 20 years of experience in key areas of digital art and print production. Roots in film based prepress with current skills in modern software applications and color management workflows. Strong management background in Prepress, Computer-to-Plate, Production Planning and Customer Service. Solution-oriented with an eye toward software evaluation, procurement, implementation and training.

- Adobe Creative Cloud 2020
- DALIM TWiST 8.6
- Fuji XMF Workflow
- Hybrid Software PACKZ
- ArtiosCAD
- Esko XL Guide
- Esko Nexus RIP
- Esko DeskPack
- ArtPro 14.0
- ColorProof XF RIP
- Chromix Curve 2.3
- KeyShot 9
- MAC OS Windows OS
- Microsoft Office
- HTML, CSS, JS

Training: Certified FTA Prepress Operator Level 1, 2, 3

Experience



Prepress Production Artist

Harbor Freight Tools

Aug 2018 - Present (2 years 6 months +)

- Create and administer Dalim TWiST automation workflows
- · Conduct daily Photoshop work for web and print related marketing material
- Design web banners and animated gif files to help teams under time crunch.
- Color correct images to meet internal guidelines to best present products to consumer channels
- Compose stock images with product photography to meet internal leadership vision
- Render 3D product files in Keyshot 9 using manufacturing cad files. Apply textures, materials, and lighting sources to product 3D files for multi-channel marketing content used by cross-functional teams.
- As needed, analyze current workflows to reduce production timelines and implement new software to improve and automate production tasks..



Engineering Technician 3 - Prepress

VIAVI Solutions

Aug 2013 - Jan 2018 (4 years 6 months)

Administer Nexus Rip workflows for flexo operation running on a Windows servers. Prepare files for press using ArtPro and Adobe CS Suite. Image Cyrel plates using Esko Spark 2530 and Dupont thermal Fast system. Calibrate press and proof output using FTA First 4.0 and G7 methology.

📘 Prepress & CAD Design Manager

Ultimate Paperbox Co.

Oct 2011 - Aug 2013 (1 year 11 months)

Manage daily operation of Prepress and CAD Department utilizing Mac and Windows based workstations. Administer Nexus RIPs on Windows servers. Perform in-house structural designs responsibilities and sample cutting duties. Train personnel on file processing of customer artwork, proofing, and day-to-day RIP operation. Supervise color management workflow to maintain G7 certification for proof and pressroom.

Production Supervisor

Superior Lithographics

Oct 2008 - Mar 2011 (2 years 6 months)

Supervised the Prepress, Computer-to-Plate, CAD, and Production Planning departments. Scheduled prepress and press workload and directed daily production meetings. Drafted and documented production procedures to improve job planning and plant processing of raw materials to finished product. Implemented cost saving procedures that reduced waste in several departments.

Electronic Prepress Manager/CAD Designer

Superior Lithographics

Oct 2006 - Oct 2008 (2 years 1 month)

Launched folding carton division of Superior Lithographics by installing and learning ArtiosCAD software. Also, installed, learned, and operated Gerber Profile Sample table, and trained personnel to use software and hardware to meet sales demand for carton quotes through final delivery of product. Supervised Prepress Dept. while taking on challenge of launching folding carton division for Superior Litho.

SUPERICR Electronic Prepress Manager

Superior Lithographics

Sep 2000 - Oct 2008 (8 years 2 months)

Converted the Prepress Dept. from traditional film based operation to digital Mac based operation. Installed Nexus and Odystar RIP's and trained personnel on day-to-day operation. Trained and implemented on color management that led to G7 cerification.

SUPERIOR Production Coordinator

Superior Lithographics

Jun 1999 - Sep 2000 (1 year 4 months)

Worked directly with customers to submit orders into production. I processed incoming purchase orders, created job tickets, reviewed and submitted electronic art files to prepress for proof approval and scheduled press time for all open jobs. I was responsible for tracking order through every department to

insure on-time delivery of finished goods. Reviewed and submitted all completed orders to accounting for immediate end-of-month billing.

Education

⊗[™] Zero To Mastery Academy

Certificate Course, Front-end Developer 2020 - 2021

California State University, Los Angeles

BS, Industrial Technology-Print Management 1998 - 2002

East Los Angeles College

Associate's degree, Liberal Arts and Sciences/Liberal Studies 1995 - 1998

Skills

Prepress • CtP • ArtiosCAD Design • G7 for Proof and Press • Customer Service • Gerber Profile 407 • Nexus Workflow Administration • Production Scheduler • Adobe Creative Suite • Mac OS X